kongapay.com 2017-09-12

# KongaPay - Online Payment | Pay Bills | Make Transfers | Free Merchant Accounts Setup

#### 1\. Introduction

KongaPay and our affiliate companies (together " **KongaPay** " or " **We** " or " **Our** ") are totally committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. 

When you sign up or use the [KongaPay Website](http://www.kongapay.com/) or Mobile Applications, you accept and consent to the practices described herein.

We at KongaPay take the processing of your information very seriously and will use same strictly in the manner herein described. For the purposes of this KongaPay Privacy Policy the term "information" refers to any confidential and/or personally identifiable or other information related to users of KongaPay Services (Customers and Merchants inclusive). 

Our Privacy Policy, Terms and Conditions and any other documents therein referred sets out the basis through which any private data we collate from you, or provided to us by you, will be processed and utilized by us. Do read the information herein provided carefully to help you understand our views and practices in relation to your "personal data" and how these will be treated by us. Your information will not be sold or rented to third parties for purposes such as marketing without having first obtained your consent. Please note that in our pursuit to better serve you and enhance the quality of our services, we will under limited circumstances share some (only as necessary) of your information with third parties under very strict stipulations. (Please read sections 3,4,5). 

##### Updating our Privacy Policy and Notification of Changes:

We reserve the right to revise our Privacy Policy over time in order to accommodate new/improved features which may be added to the KongaPay Services or as we incorporate suggestions from our customers. In light of these we may change this Privacy Policy at any time by posting a revised version of it on our website. We will provide you with at least 30 days' prior notice of the effective date of the revised privacy policy. In the event that we do not, we will have legal basis for such. The notice may be via email or "Policy Updates" page on our website. As of the effective date of the revised privacy policy, you will be considered as having consented to all changes to the Privacy Policy. If you disagree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, you may close your account at any time. 

##### Third Party Websites:

Any information you provide directly to a third party merchant, website or application is not covered by this privacy notice. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any third party to whom you choose to share your personal information directly as we are not responsible for the privacy or security practices of the third parties with whom you choose to share your personal information directly. Please note that KongaPay will not collect information from children under the age of 18. All children must therefore be monitored by their parents and guardians. 

#### 2\. Information We Collect From You

##### Information required from you:

To use the KongaPay Services, you must provide certain information, this may be gotten when you fill forms on the website and mobile applications while you register, participate in social media functions on our site, promotion or survey and when you report a problem on our site. This information includes, but is not limited to your name, address, phone number, and email address. In order to make payments through the KongaPay Services, you must provide your photograph, financial and debit card information. We may also request that you choose and answer different security questions. 

##### Information collected while using your device to access KongaPay:

The use of KongaPay Services on any device (e.g. Laptops, Phones etc.) warrants we automatically collect technical information e.g. Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform; the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time); products you viewed or searched for; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call our customer service number. Also when you use KongaPay to send money, we ask that you provide certain relevant information related to the transaction. We collect these bits of information to cross check the information provided to us in order to help detect possible instances of unauthorized transactions and also to ensure that the cards and/or Financial information is not stolen . 

##### Information relating to you collected from other sources:

KongaPay verifies all the information you provide in order to protect all our customers from potential fraud. If you register a credit card or debit card or bank account with KongaPay, we will verify your Bank Verification Number "BVN" from your bank, thereby confirming if your bank and card information match what is supplied by you to KongaPay and that the card has not been reported as lost or stolen. We may receive information about you if you use any of the other websites we operate or the other services we provide. We also work closely with third parties e.g. business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment services, analytics providers, search information providers and may receive information about you from them. 

##### Cookies, Web Beacons, Local Storage and Similar Technologies:

When you use KongaPay Services or access our website, we (including companies we work with) may place small data files on your computer or other devices. (E.g. cookies, pixel tags, "Flash cookies," or other local storage provided by your browser). Cookies are used to recognize you as a Merchant or Buyer, customize KongaPay Services, content, measure promotional effectiveness, help ensure that your account security is not compromised, mitigate risk and prevent fraud, and to promote trust and safety across our website and the KongaPay Services offered to you. 

Please note that you are at liberty to decline cookies unless the cookies are specifically required to prevent fraud or ensure the security of the websites we control. However declining our cookies may interfere with your use of KongaPay Services. 

##### Account Information:

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, "Account Information" includes without limitation: name, address, email address, phone number, username, photograph, IP address, device ID, geolocation information, account numbers, account types, details of funding instruments associated with the account, details of payment transactions, details of commercial transactions, customer statements and reports, account preferences, details of identity collected as part of our "know your customer" checks on you, and customer correspondence". 

#### 3\. Use Of Information We Collect From You

##### Internal Uses:

We collect, store and process your information. The primary purpose for this is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient and customized experience for your use. The information collected from you in the ways expatiated below: 

  * Verification of your identity, including during account creation and password reset processes
  * Processing transactions and provision of the KongaPay Services
  * Managing, preventing and detection of risk and/or remediate fraud or other potentially illegal or prohibited activities
  * Resolution of disputes, collection of fees, and troubleshooting problems
  * Detect, prevent or remediate violations of policies or applicable user agreements
  * Provide you with quality customer support services
  * Improve the KongaPay Services by customizing your user experience
  * Measure the performance of the KongaPay Services and improve their content and layout
  * Manage and protect our information technology infrastructure

The use of questionnaires, surveys and your profile data is to improve KongaPay Services or as otherwise explained in detail in the survey itself. However you may choose not to complete surveys or questionnaires.

##### Communication with KongaPay Customers:

We communicate with our users on a regular basis via email (sometimes SMS’s) to provide requested services.

We also communicate with our users via phone calls for the following purposes:

  * Resolve all customer complaints or claims made by users of the KongaPay Services
  * Respond to all requests for customer service
  * Onform users if we believe their accounts have been compromised or any of their transactions have been used for an illegitimate purpose
  * Confirm information concerning a user's identity, business or account activity
  * Conduct customer surveys
  * Investigate any suspicious transactions

We send emails to you to:

  * Confirm your subscription to our KongaPay services
  * Send you notice of payments that you send or receive through KongaPay
  * Send you information about important changes to our products and services
  * Send notices and other communiques as required by law. Please note that users cannot opt out of these communications, as they will be primarily informational in nature rather than promotional.

We also use your email address to send you other types of communications including "News from KongaPay", customer surveys and notice of special third-party promotions. 

We may communicate with you as described above by SMS (Please note that SMS’s will be treated as an email for the purpose of managing your Communication Preferences).

In connection with independent audits of our financial statements and operations, the auditors may seek to contact a sample of our customers to confirm that our records are accurate. However, these auditors cannot use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

#### 4\. Sharing your information with other KongaPay users

A duly registered KongaPay user’s information is made available to other Konga Pay customers whom you have paid or senders who are attempting to pay using the KongaPay services. This information includes name and contact details (if applicable). If you are a Business account holder, we will also display to other KongaPay customers the website address (URL) and customer service contact information that you provide us. In addition, this and other information may also be shared with third parties when you use these third parties to access KongaPay Services. However, your debit/credit card number, bank account and other financial information will not be revealed to anyone whom you have paid or who has paid you through the KongaPay Services or third parties that use the KongaPay Services, except with your express permission or if we are required to do so pursuant to debit/credit card rules, a court order or other legal process. 

If you log into external websites or mobile apps via KongaPay we may share your login status with any third party offering this Service as a login method, as well as the personal and other Account Information that you consent to being shared so that the third party can recognize you. 

Please note that KongaPay will not give such third party access to your KongaPay Account and payments will only be made from your Account to that third party with your consent upon specific authorization given by you. Do note that you have total control over the settings for any such data sharing when logged into your KongaPay account. 

We work with third parties including merchants to enable them to accept or facilitate payments from or to you using the KongaPay Services. In doing so, a third party may share information about you with us such as your email address or phone number, when a payment is sent to you or when you are attempting to pay that third party. We in turn use this information to confirm that you are a KongaPay customer and that KongaPay can be enabled to make a payment, or where a payment is sent to you to send you a notification that you have received a payment. Also, if you request that we validate your status as a KongaPay customer with a third party, we will do so. Please note that third parties you buy from and contract with may have their own privacy policies, and KongaPay is not responsible for their operations, including but not limited to their information practices. 

Acceptance of this Privacy Policy, means you expressly agree and consent that each time you pay or attempt to pay another KongaPay customer (including a merchant) using your KongaPay account, KongaPay may transfer the aforementioned relevant data to such KongaPay customer. 

In order to process, execute or otherwise deal with and provide information about the payment, you also expressly agree and consent to KongaPay providing transactional information and other information necessary for the use of a KongaPay mobile application (including point of sale products) to a merchant or another KongaPay customer who you have explicitly selected or chosen using the KongaPay mobile application or point of sale product. 

#### 5\. When And How We Share Information With Third Parties

KongaPay works with third-party service providers who provide important services which enable us to offer easier, faster, and safer ways to make payments. In light of this we will only disclose user data as the need arises to enable them perform the services required. 

You specifically give your consent to KongaPay to do any and all of the following with your information: 

**Disclosure of necessary information to:** the police and other law enforcement agencies; security forces; competent governmental bodies; (other than tax related authorities), regulatory authorities, and other third parties, including KongaPay affiliates, that we have reason to believe it is appropriate for us to cooperate with in investigations of fraud or other illegal activities or potential illegal activities, or to conduct investigations of violations of our Terms and Conditions. 

We and other organizations, including parties that accept KongaPay, may also share, access and use necessary information to help us prevent fraud, money laundering and terrorist financing. These agencies include but are not limited to Special Frauds Unit (SFU) Economic and Financial Crime Commission etc. 

We will also disclose necessary information in response to the requirements of a civil or criminal legal process. 

If you as a merchant use a third party to access or integrate KongaPay, we may disclose to any such partner necessary information for the purpose of facilitating and maintaining such an arrangement (including, without limitation, the status of your KongaPay integration, whether you have an active KongaPay account and whether you may already be working with a different KongaPay integration partner). 

Disclose necessary information to the payment processors, auditors, customer services providers, fraud agencies, financial products providers, commercial partners, operational services providers, agencies, marketplaces and other third parties listed here. Please note that the purpose of this disclosure is to allow us to provide KongaPay Services to you. 

**Customer Service:** for customer service purposes, including to help service your accounts or resolve disputes (e.g., billing or transactional). 

**Mergers or Acquisitions:** As with any other business, it is possible that in the future KongaPay could merge with, or be acquired by, another company. If such an acquisition occurs, you consent to the successor company having access to the information maintained by KongaPay, including customer Account Information, and such successor company would continue to be bound by this Privacy Policy unless and until it is amended. 

**Third Party Sites:** If you open a KongaPay account directly on a third party website or via a third party application, any information that you enter on that website or application (and not directly on a KongaPay website) will be shared with the owner of the third party website or application. These sites are governed by their own privacy policies and you are encouraged to review their privacy policies before providing them with personal information. KongaPay is not responsible for the content or information practices of such third parties. 

#### 6\. Protection Of Information

KongaPay is entirely committed to protecting the information we collect from you. We maintain appropriate administrative, technical and physical safeguards (i.e. firewalls, data encryption, competent security guards etc.) All this is in place so as to prevent accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use. 

Please note that you are vested with the responsibility of protecting your password in its entirety as communicated in our Terms and Conditions. You must not share your KongaPay Password with anyone. We will never request for your passwords via email or SMS. In the event you receive such communiques, please disregard and forward same communiqués to [support@kongapay.com](mailto:support@kongapay.com.). In the event you share your password with a third party, you will be held responsible for the consequences. If you believe your password has been compromised please change it immediately and contact us. 

#### 7\. Our Contact

KongaPay ensures that our day-to-day processes comply with this privacy policy and we are always available to address any questions or enquiries in relation to this "Privacy Policy". You can contact us to update information we have about you. Please send an email to [support@kongapay.com](mailto:support@kongapay.com.) or call us on [0809 999 0295](tel:08099990295).
